<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>By the King. A proclamation commanding all the trained bands and others on this side Trent, to be in readinesse with horse and arms, to serve His Majestie for defence of the kingdome.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B13182</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99892511</idno>
  <idno type="VID">185872</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240921054</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">STC 9169</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 816.m.1[35]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S122978</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99892511</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99892511e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B13182)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185872)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C3:1[35])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>By the King. A proclamation commanding all the trained bands and others on this side Trent, to be in readinesse with horse and arms, to serve His Majestie for defence of the kingdome.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1625-1649 : Charles I)</author>
                  <author>Charles I, King of England, 1600-1649.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2] sheets.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Robert Barker, printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty: and by the assignes of John Bill,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1640.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end: York the last day of August in the sixteenth yeer of our reign.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Arms 24; Steele notation: the cellour, 2) Lieutenan- be.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Scotland --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:185872:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
                  <q>HONI SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
                  <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>❧ By the King.</head>
            <head>❧ A Proclamation commanding all the Trained Bands and others on this side Trent, to be in readinesse with Horse and Arms, to serve His MAJESTIE for defence of the KINGDOME.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas His Majessie (now in person with His Armio in the</hi> North, against those Rebels of <hi>Scotland,</hi> who have entred this Kingdom with Hostility and Arms) hath in His absence, for the safeguard of the Queen, Prince, and the rest of His Royall Children, and of all His Subjects in these Southern parts of the Realm, by Commission under the great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed His right trustie and right welbeloved Cousin and Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellour, <hi>Thomas</hi> Earl of <hi>Arundel</hi> and <hi>Surrey,</hi> Earl Marshall of <hi>England,</hi> to be His Captain Generall of all His Forces to be raised on this side <hi>Trent,</hi> and in His Dominion of <hi>Wales;</hi> to be commanded and disposed of by the said Earl, as occasion shall require.</p>
            <p>And whereas His Majestie by His Letters under His Signet, directed to His Lieute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of His severall Counties on this side <hi>Trent,</hi> and in <hi>Wales,</hi> hath required and authorized them to have in readinesse the Trained Bands, with such further Forces of Horse and Foot as can be raised in those Counties, and in their own persons to bring them, with meet Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers to order and command them, to such Rendebous as shall be assigned to the said Lieu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenants:</p>
            <p>His Majestie therefore, doth declare His Royall will and pleasure, and doth hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire and command all his Lieutenants, and Deputy Lieutenants of his severall Counties
<pb facs="tcp:185872:2"/>on this side <hi>Trent,</hi> and in His Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> That forthwith they have in readinesse, not onely all the Trained Bands, both Horse and Foot, of their severall Lieutenan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies; but likewise all other persons, that are able, either in body or estate, to do service, to put themselves into the best order they can for Arms, both for Horse and Foot; and be ready either to defend the Counties in which they dwell, or to come under the conduct of the said Lieutenants, or their Deputy Lieutenants, or some of them, to such Rendevous elsewhere, and at such times, for the defence of the publike, and themselves, as the said Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Generall, or (in his absence) his Lieutenant shall appoint: And all to be in such readi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse, that they be able to march at four and twenty hours warning at the furthest after command to be received from him or his Lieutenant in that behalf: Wherein His Maiestie doth expect that forwardnesse in all His loyall and well affected Subjects, as that in this common danger, they will be willing with their persons and estates, to contribute all assi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance to His Majestie, for the publike preservation of the Kingdom, and their own safety and peace.</p>
            <p>And His Majestie doth further charge and command, as well as his Lieutenants and Deputy Lieutenants of his said severall Counties, as all Iustices of Peace, Maiors, She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffs, Bailiffs, and all others, whom it doth or may concern, to be obedient, aiding and as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sisting unto the directions and commands of the said Captain Generall, or his Lieutenant from time to time in the execution of this His Majesties service. Neverthelesse, his Majesties pleasure is, That for such Forces as are or shall be levied by His Majesties Captain Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rall of His Army, or His Lieutenant for his Majesties service in the North, that they shall be spared to serve in His Majesties Army on this side <hi>Trent.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Given at Our Court at York </hi>
                  <date>
                     <hi>the last day of August in the sixteenth yeer of Our Reign.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <trailer>❧ <hi>God save the King.</hi>
            </trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprinted at London by Robert Barker, Printer to the Kings most excellent Majesty: And by the Assignes of JOHN BILL. 1640.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>